A Guide to the Business Records of Pitts, Hankin & Trundle/ J.L. Pitts & Company, 1890-1924
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Business Records of Pitts, Hankin & Trundle/ J.L. Pitts & Company 1890-1924
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10985
This collection contains ca. 600 accounts and receipts (2 Hollinger boxes) and thirteen bound volumes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were given to the Library by Mrs. John Randolph Phillips of Scottsville, Virginia, on October 23, 1990.
Biographical/Historical Information
Pitts, Hankin & Trundle/ J.L. Pitts & Company were general contractors in Barber, Virginia specializing in highway construction.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of business records of the firms of J.L. Pitts, Jr. & Brothers, Barber, Virginia (main office in Scottsville, Virginia), General Contractors specializing in highway construction, and Pitts, Hankin, and Trundle, Railroad Contractors of Prestonsburg, Kentucky. These papers contain ca. 600 accounts and receipts (2 Hollinger boxes) and thirteen bound volumes, including the following types of volumes: letterbook, daybook, ledger, journal, payroll records, time book, and shipment records.
Contents List
- ACCOUNTS & RECEIPTS
  - J.L. Pitts, Jr. & Brothers 1909, 1921-1924, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Pitts, Hankin & Trundle 1903-1905, 7 folders (Box 2)
- PITTS, HANKIN & TRUNDLE
  - Payroll Records & Account Book (in a Letter Press Copy Book) 1903-1904, Bound volume
    Mentions the Lee District Sewer Contract, Big Sandy Railway Company, Langhorne, Johnson & Col, Johnson, Briggs & Pitts, Green Wells, and the "Italian Payroll"
  - Time Book 1905-1906, Bound volume
  - Letter Press Copy Book, with index, of business correspondence and some accounts [ca. 1905-1908], Bound volume
  - Daybook, Prestonburg, Kentucky, Big Sandy Contract 1903-1904, Bound volume
  - Journal 1905-1909, Bound volume
  - Personal Ledger #4, with index, East Point, Kentucky 1902-1903, Bound volume
- J.L. PITTS & COMPANY
  - Journal, with index 1890-1891, Bound volume
  - Ledger, with index, Railroad Contractor, Scottsville 1905-1906, Bound volume
  - Ledger 1917-1921, Bound volume
  - Ledger of Inspections and Shipments, with index 1917-1918, Bound volume
  - Tie and Lumber Company Record of Shipments of Railroad Ties 1917, Bound volume
  - Tie and Lumber Company Record of Shipments of Railroad Ties 1917-1918, Bound volume
  - Tie and Lumber Company Record of Shipments of Railroad Ties 1918-1921, Bound volume
    Partial volume